Inazaki is making a substitution here, replacing number four Alan Ojiro will be the team captain number one Shinsuke Kita.
We didn't get to see him in the scouting videos, did we?
I really wanted to put more pressure on Ojiro.
Hey guys, you don't have to get so tense.
I'm just a substitute.
I'm only here to keep things going.
I have nothing to be afraid of.
What will lo list?
What would you say to do like you?
You can't wait to try.
Even when you want to wait the rest of your break, we won't die.
If you wait until the end, you won't die.
Ah, she won't end up, yeah
It's the most fun thing
I don't have enough money
Say, say, don't go
Now and now, we're going to be
We're going to be able to do the truth
If you don't go
It's so interesting
It's so fun
I don't want to stop now
I'll be able to laugh
Remember, dear
There's always someone watching
All the time
The gods are everywhere around us
So someone always has their eye on you
Ginn
Why'd you force that spike earlier?
I... it felt like the tide was turning in Karasuno's favor
I wanted to do something to stop it
Oh, really?
And you think getting blocked is going to do that?
Everyone suddenly gets so on edge the instant we send Kita out there on the court
Well, his constructive criticism is pretty terrifying
Crush it, Kita!
Right in the middle
I got it!
Sorry, it's short, Junkie!
With the center all the way in the back, he aimed right for the spikers' path to the net
Akagi!
Got it!
It's a chance ball!
Yes!
Akagi!
Got it!
It's a chance ball!
I hate this play
Inanizaki reaches break point!
That one is gonna hurt Karasuno!
Get him!
Inanizaki reaches breakpoint!
That one is gonna hurt Karasuno.
I have a bad feeling about this.
We're in enough trouble with them getting that breakpoint.
It's like my boys could've won that rally a few minutes ago,
and now suddenly, they can't.
Once in a while, you find Akita.
A real influence.
He's certainly not a star player, but his presence takes over the whole court.
You know, he's had that kind of effect ever since junior high.
They're number four. He won't do line shots.
Good catch!
Every move he made was for a reason.
Every word he said was precise.
His play may have been unpolished, but very deliberate.
And now, Akita is brimming with confidence.
Not a confidence that assumes he's a better player than the others.
But with an assurance that he won't mess anything up.
Come on. How is Akita suddenly the hero when he just got out there?
He's got way more XP than you, that's how.
Actually, I heard Akita wasn't put in any official games at all.
At least until he was a third year anyway.
What? Are you kidding me?
Every time I've seen him play, he's like a total seasoned veteran.
Even if you weren't a bench warmer in middle school, you still might not get many chances to play for this team.
True, but I heard he didn't get on the court in middle school either.
In fact, he never even got a uniform in all three years.
Huh?
I don't understand the purpose of getting nervous.
What?
Seriously, you some kind of robot or something?
I mean, I've had my suspicions.
People only get nervous when trying to be better than usual, trying to do abnormal things.
I mean, uh, think about it.
It never makes you nervous doing everyday things like eating or using the toilet.
It should be the same with volleyball.
If it's something you can do during practice, there's no reason to get nervous, is there?
Give him hell!
Oh, look. Karasuno's first year relief server's in there.
He's pretty good at scoring, isn't he?
That felt like a good one.
Kida's skills are, well, better than average.
He's not especially superior when it comes to physical or technical stuff.
But, if there's something he can do in practice, he can absolutely pull it off in a game.
The best praise you can give him is to just trust that he'll be fine.
Hey, what's up, Atsumu?
Did you catch a cold?
Shouldn't you, like, be at home in bed?
This is nothing!
I'll get worse if I don't play volleyball!
Yeah.
That's the spirit.
The true sportsman.
I like it!
Go home.
Huh?
Don't praise people for failing to take care of themselves.
What?
Why am I in trouble?
Ice cold.
No, I'm gonna catch a cold.
What the hell was that crap?
Ah!
Couldn't that jerk have been a little nicer about it?
Huh?
You're gonna make me cry!
Pickled plums?
It's so sweet!
Every day.
You have to keep it up every day.
Taking care of your health.
Cleaning.
Tidying up.
Thank you for the food.
Saying please and thank you.
And volleyball.
Hmm.
Don't worry about him.
Hmm?
Doing that is just his daily ritual.
The gods are everywhere.
All around you, all the time.
That's what my grandma would always tell me.
But eventually, it stopped mattering to me.
It's not like I'm doing this for the gods.
Repetition.
Routine.
Conscientiousness.
They make me feel good.
Always watching all the time.
Number one.
Keyed up.
Yes, sir.
Next up, number 2.
Omimi.
Yes, sir.
This kind of makes sense.
Deep down, I always thought that Kito was kind of a robot.
Mm-hmm.
Grown-ups like to say
It's not about the results
It's about the process
But you know, kids aren't like that
But results are everything
But I entirely agree
With the adults on this one
My daily actions
Add up to make me who I am
The results are nothing more than
Byproducts
It's not like I'm gonna be a professional volleyball player
For a living, but
Maybe this
Counts as a result
Who cares about the details?
Emotions don't need a reason
If you're freaking happy, you can just be freaking happy
Know what I mean?
Dude, what the hell's so funny?
You're right
I'm not here for the applause
I'm here
To do what I do
If Alan, Rintaro, and Atsumu
Are the kind of players
Who throw the other team into despair
Kido's role
Is to prolong that despair
And Anasaki has reached set point
Don't quit
You're only eight points behind
Keep kicking ass
They're probably going to lose this set
The question is how
The end of the second set
Will set the tone for the final set of the match
Yes, sir
Please let this end on a positive note
Ah, good, good
Looks like this set is ours, huh?
You never know
Last year, the other team came back from behind
Even though we had a six-point lead
They could go for a new record here
Huh?
These first and second years are still at a difficult age
Seriously
It's not like he ever yells or hits anyone
But he's still so intimidating
He's just so guarded on every level
He's already here
I don't suppose there's a shortcut somewhere
A failing grade?
What's that?
I wish I could get him with his guard down
Like, for example
Maybe one day I can catch him using baby talk
When he's talking to a pet
There's a good little boy
I don't put Kido in just to strengthen our defense
Whenever they get too far ahead
The second years will either rush to win
Or get complacent
They may be our main guns
But mentally, they're still children
They need someone to keep them in line
And that someone is Kido
Atsumu is aggressive and competitive
But that sometimes works against us
Osamu may seem commoner than Atsumu
But they have the same DNA
Gin is passionate and wants to help the team
Which can make him rush to score a point
As soon as starts to slack off
As soon as we have strong lead or victories in sight
I'm watching all of you
Their number five turned everything around
At the end of the first set
In that case
I'll use my serves
To drag him back down
They may be ahead
But they are not holding back
Yes
Tense ball
Here it comes
Just try and stop me
A powerful serve followed by an even more powerful quick attack
And just like that
The second set goes to Inarizaki
Karasuno was absolutely powerless to stop them
Those quigs from Inarizaki's number ten are unstoppable
Yeah
And Karasuno's blockers have good reflexes
But their defense is full of holes
True
Inarizaki keeps targeting the same guy
Come after me already
Alright boys
Let's get it in gear
Hoorayah
I've never seen Nishinoya so quiet when he's not on the court
I like to think it's because he's concentrating but
You're doing that thing you do whenever you mess up during practice
Remember
Take it easy
Pull yourself together man
You practiced your butt off
You got this
Hey everything's fine
Yeah right
Nishinoya
You can do this man
Actually I can't guarantee that
I mean his serve is so intense that even you're having trouble with it
That's Atsumumiya's serve
It's awesome
Yeah I'm sorry
I completely suck at encouraging other people
I'm too busy dealing with my own stuff
I'll just deal with me
No matter what the pass
I'll get points
I don't need A-passes either
Just get them to me high
Wow
Listen Kageyama
We need to talk about your timing
Huh?
What's your problem?
Great speech Asahi
Yeah?
I think it kind of fell apart
Atsumu
You saw Karasuno's setter serve earlier
And now you want to do a spike serve right?
You think it'd be so much cooler to just blast a spike serve past him
And you're tired of jump floaters
How does he know?
Your jump floaters are scoring well right now
If you're gonna crush their libero
Then go crush him
Yes sir
The ultimate challenger in Nadazaki
Alright let's go
Yeah
Or the unknown old contender Karasuno
Which team will reach the top first?
This fateful third set starts off with a serve from Atsumumiya
How many is that now?
That's big time server Atsumumiya
Starting off the third set with a service ace right from the get-go
I was sure it was going out myself
Atsumu is really on his game today
I bet he could score with a spike serve if he tried
Sure
The chances of him getting it over are basically equal either way
Hmm?
Didn't you just tell him to stick with jump floaters?
Both of Atsumu's serves are extremely powerful
But
If he switches to a spike serve and the other team manages to get it
He'll end up thinking that he should have gone with the jump float serve
And that will stick with him the rest of the game
Whereas
If he hits a really good jump floater and they get it
Knowing Atsumu's personality
It would rev up his competitive side
And get him to play even harder
So as far as this match goes
I think sticking to jump floaters is a better choice
To keep him engaged
The weird part is he's always right about this stuff
I feel like my feet are nailed to the floor
I can tell I'm responding slower than usual
Oh yeah
This is it
This is what fear feels like
I'm on the left side
Asahi!
Yes!
Nice kill, man!
Wow, look at that Asahi's being all dependable
Nishinoi is human
He has the right to get overwhelmed every once in a while too
It looks to me like Karasuno switched their rotation up
Subaru, feel free to share your expert commentary
Huh?
Oh, I, uh
If there's one thing that makes volleyball's rules unique
I'd say it's the player rotation system
That's where, whenever the team gets a new turn at serving
All the players have to rotate positions clockwise
Each team decides their starting order before a set
And submits it to the organizers
For example, one common rotation is for the setter to start off in the back row
Using that combination means there will be three solid attackers up front right off the bat
It's also pretty common to start off with the strongest server
For Narazaki, their setter is also their best server
So they get both strategies at once
Which means this is probably a permanent starting rotation for them
They're telling opponents to try whatever they want
We have a rotation that works no matter what
And here it is
On the other hand, Karasuno feels like a team that just dives in head first
But they also seem like the type to actually use a lot of trial and error
Narazaki seems pretty evenly strong in any rotation
But I'm guessing their attack stat is highest when number 4, number 10, and number 11 are up front
Karasuno's strengths are more polarized
Especially their middle blocker spot
Their mini number 10 is so specialized in attack
They can put him anywhere
And he doesn't care
He'll be a point-scoring machine
He's also a very effective decoy
Their four-eyed number 11 seems to be the keystone of their defense
So you'd want to put him wherever the other team's attackers are strongest
No, maybe they should be putting everything they have into shutting down the serve for Matsumumiya
But doing that, they couldn't start with a power server
The setter or the samurai
Nobody likes a blabbermouth know-it-all
Sorry, I've been talking way too much
I think I've got this part
If Inarizaki is in the same rotation but Karasuno changed theirs
That means when players from Inarizaki attack
They'll be in the same position but up against new Karasuno blockers
That's it! Exactly right!
All the matchups are going to be different
Every time the rotations change
We'll get to see a different little battle play out
Alan!
Got it!
Karasuno has already picked off Ojiro with their serve
A super-fast quick attack!
One touch!
Yes!
How does it help for you to freak out?
I'm betting this is why Karasuno chose this rotation
The way things are now
The twins' quick attack will keep matching up with old four-eyes
Alright, let's switch up our rotation
When Matsumumiya is serving
He's gonna aim at Nishinoya every single time
Whether he's positioned in the middle or not
Ha! Obsessed much?
Tsukishima, I'm gonna have you match up with Osamumiya and Rintaro Tsuna more often
Countering the twins quick
Yeah, because that was the biggest surprise we've had to deal with from them
We're counting on you, you weirdo quick killer
Uh, okay
The Hinata Inuoka strategy was actually working pretty good
But unfortunately, I think Tanaka's getting tired of always having to jump up to block in Hinata's place
I'd honestly like to tell you it's all good
But being in the middle sucks
So Tsukishima, jealous I got put in charge of something important?
Uh-oh, looks like I just stole your big important job
Tsukishima never neglects his trash talk
The guy's a pro
It's an art form, really
Samu, look!
Alex!
Ojiro is definitely the guy we need to keep from getting hot
So for this third set
I want to put one more blocker in his way
And he is shut down
First-year Tobio Kageyama blocked Inanazaki's ace, Alen Ojiro, all on his own
Karasuno takes the lead with a brilliant play
That announces to the world that this will not be a repeat of the second set
Nationals has always had some amazing blockers
I couldn't even tell you how many times I've been shut down
They come at me so fast, it's like I'm frozen in time
Sometimes they're in front of me before I can even try to attack
Those hands stretching out over me are sheer terror incarnate
In fact, a block that doesn't scare the crap out of you isn't a real block at all
Who knew a setter
Would be an even more terrifying blocker than Four Eyes over there
確かなことはいつか
分かる時が来るから
間違ったっていいさ
今思いを止めないで
現実が飛んじゃうような
夢が欲しかったのに
辻褄を合わすだけの日々は
味気ない
何にも怖くなんて泣いて
強がって馬鹿の少年が
今もまだ汗ばむ背中を見つめてるから
奇跡はもういらない
どこまでだって
いける僕らはファンで
夢も叶うさ
ここまでやってきたのは
偶然なんかじゃなくて
さてしまう舞台に
だって
痛いといつでも
強く願い続けた
君がそこにいたから
次回は
HERO
スピード
アーレーン
リキャ смог
マネザイダー
ヤン
イフェー
もうちょっと
さっくり
ナ owning
福
こんにちは